Captain Corelli's Mandolin is a drama, romance,
war film directed by John Madden.
When a fisherman leaves to fight with the Greek army during World War II,
his fiancée falls in love with the local Italian commander.
Captain Antonio Corelli, played by Nicolas Cage.
Pelagia, played by Penélope Cruz.
Dr. Iannis, played by John Hurt.
Mandras, played by Christian Bale.
Captain Günther Weber, played by David Morrissey.
Drosoula, played by Irene Papas.
Captain Corelli's Mandolin is a 2001 war film directed by John Madden.
It is based on the 1994 novel Captain Corelli's Mandolin by Louis de Bernières.
The film pays homage to the thousands of Italian soldiers executed at the Massacre of the Acqui Division by German forces in
Cephalonia in September 1943, and to the people of Cephalonia who were killed in the post-war earthquake.
The novel's protagonists are portrayed by actors Nicolas Cage and Penélope Cruz.
The film explores themes of allies, greek island,
mandolin, resistance fighter, greek history.
The tone is emotional.